

I love to bring the joy of Google Cloud Platform and Big Data to businesses and humans alike. Was at the birth of Google Enterprise. Have been architecting, selling & building GCP solutions for many different organisations for over 9 years, building over a hundred GCP projects for customers.

Paul is a Google Certified Cloud Architect & Data Engineer who has worked extensively with GCP over the past 9 years, winning several industry awards for GCP work. Paul has worn many hats from developer to lead architect, trainer, team lead and SCRUM master.

Paul's skillset combines a mixture of GCP architecture, consultancy and engineering which lends itself perfectly to this role. He is comfortable operating at many levels from developer to CEO and brings a lot of experience in designing and engineering GCP to demonstrate ideas and prove concept through to building production-ready technical solutions including data modelling through to architecting to security requirements.

Paul has built over 100 GCP projects from secure datamarts and dashboards to advising on VPC networks and setting up a dedicated interconnect - I am experienced with the whole GCP product set.

Paul is also an experienced developer advocate and educator who enjoys delivering training sessions & leading/advising tech teams.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **PA Consulting/Rentokil,** crawley — Google Cloud Platform Specialist

DECEMBER 2018 - APRIL 2019 Provided GCP consulting and built an automated data mart API solution:

- Member of SCRUM delivery team
- Provided architectural guidance Developed, load-tested & documented a fully-automated data-mart/API solution using App Engine, BigQuery, Cloud Endpoints and Colaboratory

## **Jaguar Land Rover,** midlands — Google Cloud Platform Specialist

JANUARY 2017 - November 2018 - Member of the BI Centre of Excellence, i've been working with JLR over 4 years:

 Provided GCP advice (selling GCP) to over 20 teams across JLR from autonomous car; pub/sub/dataflow/CloudML at scale, global marketing reporting using google sheets, BigQuery, Datastudio, Colaboratory. i've built projects using most GCP APIs from serverless through Kubernetes

#### **Appsbroker,** swindon — Google Cloud Evangelist

AUGUST 2014 - NOVEMBER 2016

Half 'cloud architect' half 'salesperson'. My job was to talk to customers,

50 North Road Bristol BS6 5AF

#### 07703 098223

pablocraig@gmail.com https://plus.google.com/u/0/+PaulCraig0 https://www.linkedin.com/in/paulcraig

#### **SKILLS**

Google Cloud Platform

Cloud architecture

Building demonstrators to aid the sales process

Public speaking

Team leading

DISRUPTING (when the time's right)

PMO/PMBOK (2006)

PRINCE2 (2007)

Agile SCRUM Master (2007)

Dozens of Google courses

#### **AWARDS**

NHS big data project of the year

**NHS** <u>european cloud innovation</u> winner

**MET OFFICE** best use of cloud technology

MET OFFICE best use of collaboration

#### **SELECTED PUBLIC SPEAKING**

BCS London 2013 - Using Agile to build a cloud solution for the Met Office

BCS London 2014 - NHS & Big Data

architect solutions, liaise with design authorities, create SoWs, get signoff, handover my baby to the delivery team.

### PA Consulting, london & boston, ma - Managing Consultant

SEPTEMBER 1994 - AUGUST 2014

Nearly two decades of life at a mid-tier management consultancy. Started as a developer, then progressed quickly through team leading, architecture then onto sales and building the best client relationships.

#### **CLOUD AND BIG DATA**

I have been educating, selling, building, evangelising on cloud and Big Data for over 8 years after partnering with Google on many successful projects. I've worked closely with Qlik technologies (helped beta-test their first QV/BQ connector), Tableau and BIME technologies.

I have a proven track-record in disrupting with big data - working for PA Consulting I was the first person to get NHS data onto Google BigQuery with the full permission from the NHS Information Centre in 2012. With this data and QlikView we were able to demonstrate the power of BigQuery and QlikView to hundreds of people at over 50 NHS sessions. Fast forward two years (where the data resided securely on Google) and an MP creates an explosion.

In all, I would say with the awards and opportunities cloud and, in particular, big data has me on an excellent adventure - one which I wish to continue with the right team.





#### **NOTEWORTHY**

In my 20 years at PA, I have experienced every facet of professional services including delivery, sales, line management and training.

Have lived/worked in Boston for 5 years. In the UK for the remainder.

I've been working alongside the Google Cloud Platform team for 8 years - a strong network is the key to getting fast service at Google.

In 2010 I was a key player in building the first Google business inside PA - team, collateral, plan, sales.

Have provided consultancy/professional services work for over 50 clients.

Have proper personally-attributed sales of £6million in the past 5 years.

#### **SELECTED BRAGGING**

Was **lead dev** on a project to build and deploy a new Internet-based solution to track postal flows in 1996! Netscape v4 cost £30/seat. I used a VB CGI library to build it

Was **dev team lead** for the first NatWest Online in 1999

Was **project manager** with tech chopsfor the **global rollout** of an LMS to Pfizer Global R&D 2001 - 2005

(in most cases) led the sale & delivered IT Strategic
Review/Assessment projects for Pfizer R&D, London Deanery, McLaren, UCAS, AstraZeneca, NIHR Clinical Research Network, ictQATAR, NHS Monitor

Project manager/SCRUM master (and also led the sale of) award-winning cloud projects for NHS England, Met Office - also Jaguar Land Rover, National Grid, Travis Perkins

Have built over 100 technical PoC/demos on Google Cloud Platform

Have demoed my Google Health Demos to over 1.000 NHS staff

Have led the sale & delivery of excellent BI projects for the NHS (x5 including the first official Google-powered dashboard for the NHS)

Have been involved in over 100 IT projects for 50 clients

Have delivered Google Cloud Platform training to over 1,000 people - of all positions

Have created and delivered professional services training to hundreds of people on many topics

Have created & delivered many training courses from coding through to successful negotiating.

I have a passion for bringing effective data visualizations to the masses - i want to ban the pie chart.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Liverpool University**, Liverpool — *BSc. Computer Science (first)* 

SEPTEMBER 1991 - JUNE 1994

**Liverpool College,** Liverpool — 4 A Levels, 11 GCSEs

SEPTEMBER 1983 - JUNE 1991

#### **SELECTED CLIENT LIST**

Google	McLaren	Universal	NatWest
NHS (over	Met Office	Music	Emirates National
10 depts)	Pepsi Cola	Pfizer	Bank of Dubai
Jaguar	·	AstraZeneca	Morrisons
Land Rover			

PAUL CRAIG pablocraigagmail.com 07703 098223

# I love to bring the joy of Google to businesses and humans alike

please click around

9 YEARS working with Google teams

Selling Google

**Delivering** 

Google

led the sale of£5MILLION of Google projects

In 2012 was key to PA winning the first ever Google Cloud Partner of the Year

Led the delivery of over 30 Google Projects value £5MILLION

Won 4 INDUSTRY AWARDS for my Google work:

**Met Office** 

NHS

Was PA's PM on the following Chrome Experiments
RACER ROLLIT

JAMWITHCHROME (rip)

Building on Google Cloud Platform (GCP)





Sharing Google Have built over 100 GCP solutions in hours/days to help customers get the best

Was the first to get NHS data onto Google - with full approval

Presented/delivered training to thousands of people

like the British Computer Society

HERE and

**HERE** 

Current job title -GCP Wizard



07703 098223 PAUL CRAIG pablocraig@gmail.com

## non-Google things of interest

## 25 YEARS EXPERIENCE

PA CONSULTING - 20

APPSBROKER - 2 Jaguar Land Rover - 3

Liverpool University 1991-1994 BSc (hons) CompSci

awards/scholarshi<mark>ps</mark>

(shortened from over 50 in total)

**Customer List** 

- \* Google NHS
- Jaguar Land Rover
- McLaren
- Met Office
- Pepsi Cola
- **Universal Music**
- Pfizer
- AstraZeneca
- NatWest

**ENFP** 

Champion

**Extraverted iNtuitive Feeling Perceiver** 

Ne Fi

- 50 the number of people i've line-managed
- PM0/PMB0K (2006)
- PRINCE2 (2007)
- Agile SCRUM Master (2007)
- Dozens of Google courses

places i've lived & worked

I enjoy jamming guitar & drums with my son